Matthew Church

churchmf@gmail.com 780-966-2257 matthewchurch.ca

Summary

Experienced, passionate, and accredited Software Developer with a focus on software engineering, user-experience, games, and tools development. C++, C#, Python and Java programmer with knowledge in operating system concepts, algorithms, and web languages. Bachelor of Computer Science and credited on multiple video games ranging from AAA sport titles to epic role playing narrative adventures. Versed in game design and computer graphics. Tools developer with knowledge in database integration, data processing, user interface design, software testing and quality analysis.

Experience

Software Developer

Bioware, Edmonton

June 2014 - Current

C#, C++, SQL, ASP.Net, JS, CSS

Designed and implemented company wide internal web applications in an agile team. Expanded scalable and intuitive tools utilized by dozens of game teams and occupations including developers, designers, testers, and managers. Improved existing workflows by integrating web applications with game engines and development tools. Attended design meetings and met with customers to improve existing systems.

Software Engineer I

Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby

July 2013 – June 2014

C++, ActionScript

Full time engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Working extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Participated in agile sprint planning in a large team in order to meet deliverable on a deadline. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and ActionScript in a massive code base.

Associate Software Engineer

Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby

January 2012 – September 2012

C++, SO

Internship on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Worked extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Took ownership of several features both new and old. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and SQL in a massive code.

Software Engineer Intern

ScriptEase Research Project, University of Alberta

May 2010 – September 2011

Java, C++, Aurora Toolset, Galaxy Editor

Developed and implemented extendable tools in a team environment which allow users to script video games without any programming experience. Attended weekly meetings emphasizing scrum planning, feature development and brainstorming. The code base grew to just over 12 000 lines during my time on the project.

Projects

"Aporkalypse" - Great Canadian Appathon 3 Entry

October 2012 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 3. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Windows Phone 7 Application.

"Umpire Strikes Back" – Great Canadian Appathon 2 Entry

October 2011 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 2. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Original/Experimental Application.

"Project Origin" - 3D Game Engine

November 2010 – December 2010

C++, OpenGL

Designed and implemented over two weeks. Able to load in any OBJ 3D model and manipulate them in an environment with line-plane collision and basic physics.

ORTS: Hierarchical Combat AI Template

November 2009 - December 2009

C++

Designed and implemented a high level real time strategy framework to facilitate artificial intelligence programming in the ORTS game engine. This multi-level approach abstracted combat to allow for easier algorithmic unit micro, squad formations and army macro.

Accredited Titles

FIFA 13 Xbox 360, PS3, PC
FIFA 14 Xbox 360, PS3, PC
2014 FIFA World Cup Brazil Xbox 360, PS3
FIFA 15 Xbox One, PS4, Xbox 360, PS3, PC
Dragon Age Inquisition Xbox One, PS4, Xbox 360, PS3, PC

Education

BSc, Computing Science Specialization

2007 - 2013

University of Alberta

Honours and Awards

Academic Excellence Scholarship Technical Achievement Best Original/Experimental Application Best Windows Phone 7 Application University of Alberta
University of Alberta 2009 Game Development Awards
Great Canadian Appathon 2
Great Canadian Appathon 3

Hobbies and Activities

Video Game Artwork and Design Club Global Game Jam Fragapalooza Annual LAN Party Recreational Soccer, Basketball, Volleyball University of Alberta Vancouver, British Columbia Edmonton, Alberta Edmonton, Alberta

References on request